<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Adelaide University Choral Society presents on Programme</title><link>https://aucs-choral.github.io/2022.06-vivaldi-programme/</link><description>Recent content in Adelaide University Choral Society presents on Programme</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://aucs-choral.github.io/2022.06-vivaldi-programme/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ave verum corpus</title><link>https://aucs-choral.github.io/2022.06-vivaldi-programme/post/ave-verum-corpus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aucs-choral.github.io/2022.06-vivaldi-programme/post/ave-verum-corpus/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Sicut cervus desiderat at fontes aquarum.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hail, true Body, born of the Virgin Mary, who having truly suffered, was sacrificed on the cross for mankind, whose pierced side flowed with water and blood. May it be for us a foretaste [of the Heavenly banquet] in the trial of death.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sicut cervus</title><link>https://aucs-choral.github.io/2022.06-vivaldi-programme/post/sicut-cervus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aucs-choral.github.io/2022.06-vivaldi-programme/post/sicut-cervus/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Sicut cervus desiderat at fontes aquarum.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like as the hart desireth the waterbrooks, so longeth my soul after Thee, o Lord.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ave Maria</title><link>https://aucs-choral.github.io/2022.06-vivaldi-programme/post/ave-maria/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aucs-choral.github.io/2022.06-vivaldi-programme/post/ave-maria/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Sicut cervus desiderat at fontes aquarum.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hail Mary, full of grace, the Lord is with thee. Blessed art thou among women, and blessed is the fruit of thy womb, Jesus. Holy Mary, Mother of God, pray for us sinners, now and in the hour of our death. Amen.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>O quam gloriosum</title><link>https://aucs-choral.github.io/2022.06-vivaldi-programme/post/o-quam-gloriosum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aucs-choral.github.io/2022.06-vivaldi-programme/post/o-quam-gloriosum/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Sicut cervus desiderat at fontes aquarum.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>O, how glorious is the kingdom,
in which all the saints rejoice with Christ!
Arrayed in white robes,
they follow the Lamb, wherever He goes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gloria (RV 289)</title><link>https://aucs-choral.github.io/2022.06-vivaldi-programme/post/gloria/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aucs-choral.github.io/2022.06-vivaldi-programme/post/gloria/</guid><description>A note about applause Unlike nearly every other form of entertainment, which encourages the communication of enjoyment, it has become a custom in the classical music world since the early 20th century not to applaud between movements of a larger work such as a concerto, mass or requiem. But in Vivaldi&amp;rsquo;s day, people would have clapped (or indeed booed, jeered and thrown fruit) whenever the mood took them. For the sake of not being glared at by people who think they know better than you, we recommend avoiding applauding until the end of the work.</description></item><item><title>About the choir</title><link>https://aucs-choral.github.io/2022.06-vivaldi-programme/choir/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aucs-choral.github.io/2022.06-vivaldi-programme/choir/</guid><description>Adelaide University Choral Society AUCS is a student club affiliated with the Adelaide University Union, founded in 1960. University of Adelaide staff and alumni also sing with the choir. We typically perform two classical concerts per year as well as a contemporary Fringe show. We have performed works from the 1500s to contemporary compositions, including motets and madrigals, masses and songs for the masses.
Soprano Olivia Arcangeli Ila Frishling Louise Jackson Phoebe Knight Hunter Loch Bethany Newhouse Bethany Poel Eleanor Packer Zoe Russell-von Bjudoss Alto Lucy Brooke Caitlin Hall Barbara Kapust Ying Le Palma Neagle Mikaela Sotiriou Annette Wheatley Rosemary Wong Tenor Lisa Buttery Jiupeng Chen Connor Fogarty Eirean James Philip Moxham Amanda Muller Bass William Bai Peter Brack Yukun Chen Simon Naylor Bruce Swanson Alistair Teagle</description></item><item><title>About the performers</title><link>https://aucs-choral.github.io/2022.06-vivaldi-programme/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aucs-choral.github.io/2022.06-vivaldi-programme/about/</guid><description>Peter Kelsall Conductor &amp;amp; Musical Director
Peter Kelsall completed his Bachelor of Music degree in 1989 at Adelaide University studying piano with Zelda Bock. He commenced organ studies with Christa Rumsey in 1987 and completed a Graduate Diploma in Performance on the instrument in 1993. In 1998 he completed his Masters Degree in Music Theory. He also holds a Certificate in Church Music from the Flinders Street School of Music TAFE and has undertaken studies in choral conducting with Carl Crossin.</description></item></channel></rss>